J. C. Wilfong, Jr. P010
People's Archive, MLK Library
J. C. Wilfong, Jr. Collection
1963-1965
People's Archive, MLK Library
Wilfong, J.C., Jr.
P010
1 Boxes
Arrangement
Basic archival procedures were used at the time of processing.
Biographical / Historical
James Chester Wilfong Jr. was an avid photographer and historian. Mr. Wilfong served as President of the PRing George's County Historical Society and wrote columns on historical houses for many publications including The Laurel Leader, The Washington Post, and The New York Times.
Custodial History
There is no deed of gift and it is uncertain as to how the library acquired these photographs.
Related Materials
D. C. Historic Preservation Division Photograph Collection, P002 James Goode "Capital Losses" Collection, P004 Hambright and Hoachlander Photograph Collection, P019
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of 32 3 x 3 inch black and white photographs. There are no negatives with this collection. The images were taken between 1963-1965 and are of houses and businesses throughout Washington, D.C., many of which have been demolished. Historic locations include the Belasco Theater, Edwin Stanton House, John Philip Sousa House, Heurich Mansion, and the Commandant's House at the USMC Barracks. Notations on many of the photographs indicate the year the building was demolished or note that the Landmarks Commission "cited" the structure. It appears that the photographs are of buildings in the district that were endangered or scheduled for demolition.
Architecture; Business; Neighborhoods; Photographs
- Series 1
  - Heubich Mansion - 1307 New Hampshire Avenue, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - House and Office - 918 10th Street, NW, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - House - 923 18th Street, NW, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Restaurant/Bet Winder Building/Riggs Bank - 17th Street, NW, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Winder Building - 604 17th Street, NW, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - House - 10th and O Street, NW, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Watterson House - 224 2nd Street, SE, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Houses - 20th and H Street, NW, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - House - 9th and I Street, SE, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Lutz Leather Goods Store - 1300 block G Street, NW, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - John Philip Sousa House - 600 block G Street, SE, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Christ Church - 600 block G Street, SE, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Houses - 700 block G Street, SE, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Commandant's House USMC Barracks - 800 block G Street, SE, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Edwin Stanton Home - 458 C Street, NW, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - House - 2030 I Street, NW, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - House - 1925 F Street, NW, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Arts Club - 2109 I Street, NW, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Howe Mansion - 1821 H Street, NW, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - House and Laundry - 913 East Capitol Street, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Turkey Thicket - 1100 Michigan Avenue, NE, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Gilman's Drug Store - 627 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Buildings - 2109 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Buildings - 600 block Indiana Avenue, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - House - 515 Massachusetts Avenue, NW, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - House - 700 block Virginia Avenue, SE, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Belasco Theatre - 17 Madison Place, NW, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Philadelphia Row - 100 Block 11th Street, SE, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - John Clagett Proctor Mausoleum - Rock Creek Cemetery, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Buildings (Eddie's Dry Cleaning) - 1114-1116 8th Street, SE, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - House - 1003 New Jersey Avenue, SE, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Houses - 911, 913 and 915 M Street, SE, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)